Guide to the Kenneth Roman Papers, 1906-2011 and undated RL.01105
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kenneth Roman papers
1906-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roman, Kenneth
RL.01105
16 Linear Feet
Kenneth Roman is a former advertising executive and CEO of Ogilvy & Mather agency, and author of several books. The collection spans the years 1906-2011 and primarily contains materials gathered during Roman's research for a biography of David Ogilvy, The King of Madison Avenue. Includes printed materials, articles, photographs, CDs, VHS videocassettes, audiocassettes of interviews with printed transcriptions, and a collection of writings and speeches by Roman and Ogilvy. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
11,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced. Contact Research Services for further information. Transcripts to interviews recorded on audiocassettes are available in the collection.
Access to the collection for commercial purposes must receive written approval from the donor prior to starting research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Kenneth Roman Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011.
Collection Overview
The Kenneth Roman Papers span the years 1906-2011 and primarily contain materials gathered during Roman's research for a biography of David Ogilvy, The King of Madison Avenue. Includes printed materials, articles, photographs, CDs, VHS videocassettes, audiocassettes of interviews with printed transcriptions, and a collection of writings and speeches by Roman and Ogilvy.
Collection Arrangement
This collection is organized alphaabetically into seven series: General Files, 1941-2011 and undated; Book Manuscript Files, 1906-2009 and undated; Interview Transcripts, 1989-2008 and undated; Speeches by Ken Roman, 1979-1989; Oversize Materials, 1947-2008; Printed Materials, 1923-2011 and undated; Audiovisual Materials, 1935-2011 and undated.
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Anthony Weir Papers
David B. McCall Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Edgar Hatcher Papers
Jock Elliott Papers
Joel Raphaelson Papers
Robert S. Smith Papers
Stephen Harty Papers
William E. Phillips Papers
Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising -- History; Advertising; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Advertising executives; Biography; Roman, Kenneth; Roman, Kenneth; Hewitt, Ogilvy, Benson & Mather; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Ogilvy & Mather; Ogilvy, Benson & Mather (New York, N.Y.); Ogilvy, David, 1911-1999
- General Files, 1941-2011 and undated
  - Binder 1
    - The Fountain Overflows--Rebecca West, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Cyril Connolly--Clive Fisher, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Myself Among Others--Ruth Gordon, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Audience Research Institute--George Gallup/David Ogilvy, 1941 (Box 1)
    - A History of British Secret Service--Richard Dean, 1969 (Box 1)
    - The Life of Ian Fleming--John Pearson, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Camp X--David Stafford, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Desperate Deception--Thomas Mahl, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Room 3603--Montgomery Hyde, 1963 (Box 1)
    - The Mirror Makers--Stephen Fox, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Binder 2
    - David Ogilvy--Dave McCall, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Honor Among Thieves--Dave McCall, undated (Box 1)
    - The Beard and I--Tommy Whitehead, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Nobody Else is Perfect--Charles Hennessy, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Of Women and Advertising--John Straiton, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Portrait--Printer's Ink, 1961 (Box 1)
    - The Story of Ted Bates & Co.--Martin Mayer, undated (Box 1)
    - Autobiography--Alan Sidnam, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Obvious Adams--Robert Ubdegraff, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Mad Men--BBC 4, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Binder 3
    - Twenty Advertisements That Shook The World--James Twitchell, undated (Box 1)
    - The Benevolent Dictators--Bart Cummings, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Madison Avenue USA--Martin Mayer, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Greatest Business Stories of All Time, 1996 (Box 1)
    - The Power of the Obvious--Alda Papone, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Ogilvy Interview--Lee Bartlett, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Ogilvy Interview 75th birthday--Joel Raphaelson, undated (Box 1)
    - Ogilvyisms--Ogilvy & Mather, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Binder 4
    - My Life--David Ogilvy, 1986 (Box 1)
    - A Gallop Through Our First 139 Years (1850-1989)--Joel Raphaelson, circa 1990 (Box 1)
    - David Ogilvy biographies, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Ogilvy & Mather timeline, key dates, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Mather & Crowther dates (Box 2)
    - David Ogilvy obituaries--Joel Raphaelson, Stanley Piggot (Box 2)
    - The Benevolent Dictators--Bart Cummings Interview, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Touffou Board Meeting--David Ogilvy, 1994 (Box 2)
    - A Life--Rebecca West, 1987 (Box 2)
  - David Ogilvy
    - David Ogilvy: Original Mad Man--BBC4, 2008 (Box 2)
    - David Ogilvy: The Most Famous Advertising Man in the World--Kenneth Roman Book Proposal, undated (Box 2)
    - David Ogilvy As I Knew Him--Michael Ball, 2008 (Box 2)
    - David Ogilvy on Creativity, undated (Box 2)
    - David Ogilvy on Training, undated (Box 2)
    - How to Create Advertising That Sells--Ogilvy & Mather house advertisements, undated (Box 2)
    - My Creative Principles, 1968 (Box 2)
    - The View From Touffou, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Eye Patch Productions
    - David Ogilvy on Creativity, 1992 (Box 3)
    - David Suskind, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Frank McGee profile, 1992 (Box 3)
    - The Importance of Direct Marketing, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Unidentified interviews (Box 3)
  - Fan letters, 2008-2010, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - How to Make $50,000 a Year in Advertising (typescript), Jud Irish, circa 1957, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Mad Men, 2009-2011 (Box 3)
  - Photograph/Art permissions, 2008-2009 (Box 4)
  - Photographs and images
    - General, 1918-2007 and undated, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Articles and printed materials, undated (Box 4)
    - Images, undated (Box 4)
    - Nick Evans on David Ogilvy, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Postcards, letters, and mailers, undated (Box 4)
  - Promotion, 2009 (Box 4)
  - Reviews, 2009 (Box 4)
  - Text permissions, 2008 (Box 4)
- Book Manuscript Files1906-2009 and undated
  - Afterward, 1952-1993 (Box 5)
  - Author's notes, 1968-2008 (Box 5)
  - Chapter 1--Family, 1953-2009, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Chapter 2--Schools, 1955-2008, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Chapter 3--A Chef/AGA, 1966-2008 (Box 5)
  - Chapter 4--History, 1906-2008 (Box 5)
  - Chapter 5--US/Gallop, 1964-2006 (Box 5)
  - Chapter 6--BSC, Amish, Overlord
    - British Security coordination, 1949-2008, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Amish, 1948-2008 (Box 6)
    - Overlord, 1947-2008 (Box 6)
  - Chapter 7--Hewitt, Ogilvy, Benson & Mather
    - Articles and advertisements, 1948-1963 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-2007, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Papers and speeches, 1948-1963, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Chapter 8--Philosopher Kings
    - Articles and advertisements, 1971-2006, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Book reviews and papers, 1961-1993 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-2008 (Box 7)
  - Chapter 9--The True Church
    - Articles, 1963-2008 (Box 8)
    - Elly Elliott memorial booklet, 2007 (Box 8)
    - Interviews and speeches, 1960-2006 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-2008, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Chapter 10--Touffou/Retirement
    - Articles and advertisements, 1973-2008, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Creative Council, 1976-1981 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-2008, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Papers, 1962-2009, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Speeches and interviews, 1970-2006 (Box 9)
  - Chapter 11--Takeover
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-2006, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Printed materials, 1985-2008, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Speeches, Interviews, and Scripts, 1986-2000 (Box 10)
    - The Ogilvy Group--Business strategy and reports, 1986-1989 (Box 11)
    - WPP Group, 1988-1990 (Box 11)
    - WPP Group plc, The Companies book, 1989 (Box 11)
    - The Yorktown Project, 1987-1989 (Box 11)
  - Chapter 12--Creative/Post-Takeover
    - Articles, 1970-1994 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970-2008 (Box 11)
    - Papers and creative, 1965-1992, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Speeches, interviews, and scripts, 1970-1994 (Box 12)
    - WPP Group miscellaneous, 1991-1997 (Box 12)
  - Chapter 13--Legacy
    - Articles and advertisements, 1997-2008, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Interviews and papers, 1991-2007 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1999-2008 (Box 12)
    - Obituaries and rememberances, 1999-2008 (Box 12)
    - Presentations and case studies, 2000-2004 (Box 12)
  - Introduction, 1982-2008 (Box 12)
  - Sources/References, 1998-2009 (Box 12)
- Interview Transcripts1989-2008 and undated
  - Binder 1
    - David Abbott, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Tony Adams, 2005 (Box 13)
    - Clive Aldred, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Don Arlett, 2007 (Box 13)
    - Louis Auchincloss, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Michael Ball, 2005-2007 (Box 13)
    - Bernard Barnett, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Lee Bartlett, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Michael Baulk, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Louis Begly, 2006 (Box 13)
  - Binder 2
    - Jimmy Benson, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Alex Biel, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Paul Biklen, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Bill/Gale Binzen, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Drayton Bird, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Doug Boumeisler, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Sue Buck, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Jeremy Bullmore, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Harold Burson/David Mitchell, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Luis Basset, 2006-2007 (Box 13)
  - Binder 3
    - Phil Carrol, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Jean Clark, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Julian Clopet, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Walter Cronkite, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Edgar Cullman, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Michael Dawson, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Helen DeKay, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Charles de Haes, 2005 (Box 14)
    - Burtch Drake, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Fran Devreaux, 2008 (Box 14)
  - Binder 4
    - Annie Fisher, 2007 (Box 14)
    - Ellie/Jack Elliot, 1989, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Nick Evans, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Jules Fine, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Richard Fowler, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Winston Fletcher, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Neil French, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Charlie Fredericks, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Lou Gerstner, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Alec and George Gallup, 2007 (Box 14)
  - Binder 5
    - Gene Grayson, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Chuck Guariglia, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Lou Harris, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Steve Hayden, 2007 (Box 14)
    - Jim Heekin, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Tony Houghton, 2007 (Box 14)
    - Jud Irish, 1999 (Box 14)
    - Ranjan Kapur/Roger Winter, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Jack Keenan, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Gene Kummel, 2006 (Box 14)
  - Binder 6
    - Leo Kelmenson, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Ian Keown, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Reva/Bill Korda, 1998 (Box 14)
    - Bob Kuperman, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Bob Lauterborn, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Mary Wells Lawrence, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Shelley Lazarus, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Gerry Lestz, 2007 (Box 14)
    - Mary Lindsay, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Peter Mayle, undated (Box 14)
  - Binder 7
    - Dick Lord, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Jane Mass/Abe Jones, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Martin Mayer, 2007 (Box 14)
    - Ed McCabe, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Bruce McCall, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Jerry McGee, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Edmund Morris, 2006 (Box 15)
    - John Nettleton, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Ed Ney, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Barry Owen, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Herta Ogilvy, 2007 (Box 15)
  - Binder 8
    - Shelby Page, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Fred Papert, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Bill Phillips, 1997, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Graham Phillips, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Jerry Pickholz, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Prince Phillip, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Archie Pitcher, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Gary Press, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Robyn Putter, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Joel Raphaelson, 1997, 2002 (Box 15)
  - Binder 9
    - John/Michael Ranck, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Keith/Rose-Lee Reinhard, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Elaine Reiss, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Vel Richey Rankin, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Harry Reid, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Bob Rightford, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Randy Rothenberg, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Brendan Ryan, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Nancy Schultz, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Gloria Sidnam, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Ted Shaw, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Dick Seclow, 2008 (Box 15)
    - Bill Whitney, 2008 (Box 15)
  - Binder 10
    - Bruce Stauderman, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Mac Stewart, 2006 (Box 15)
    - John Straiton, 2006 (Box 15)
    - William Stevenson, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Anthony Tennant, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Lee Thuna, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Francois/Simone Tiger, 2006 (Box 16)
    - John/Jill Treneman, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Sheila Trevellyan, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Mike Turner, 2006 (Box 16)
  - Binder 11
    - Emile Vassen, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Greg Waggett, 2007 (Box 16)
    - Peter/Susan Warren, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Mike Walsh, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Ellie Watrous, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Bill Weed, 2006 (Box 16)
    - Margot Wilkie, 2006 (Box 16)
    - John Williams, 2007 (Box 16)
    - Ken Roman--Interview, 2005 (Box 16)
    - Ken Roman notes, undated (Box 16)
    - Lorna Wilson, 2007 (Box 16)
- Speeches by Ken Roman1979-1989
  - Creative Training Program, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Creativity and Profitability, 1988 (Box 16)
  - How to Win New Business (training program), 1984 (Box 16)
  - Hug a Client Today, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Not a Bad Year, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Officer's Meeting (WPP tender offer), 1989 (Box 16)
  - Ogilvy & Mather 33rd Annual Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 16)
  - The 85% Solution, 1983 (Box 16)
  - The Agency of the Year, 1983 (Box 16)
  - The New Agency, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Toward a New Spirit, 1979 (Box 16)
  - Welcome (32nd staff meeting), 1980 (Box 16)
  - Welcome--In All Languages (KR final management meeting), 1989 (Box 16)
  - What It Means to Belong to the Club, 1985 (Box 16)
  - What It Takes to Be the Best Agency, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Why Brands Fail, 1983 (Box 16)
- Oversize Materials, 1947-2008
  - Chapter 6--Directive to Creative Department, A Man Called Intrepid excerpt, 1947, 1976 (Box 17)
  - Chapter 7--Articles and memoranda, 1948-1960 (Box 17)
  - Chapter 10--Articles and miscellaneous, 1973-1988 (Box 17)
  - Chapter 11--Articles, 1987-1996 (Box 17)
  - Chapter 12--Articles and miscellaneous, 1990-2008, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Chapter 13--Articles, 1999-2008 (Box 17)
  - Chapter 13--Obituaries, 1999 (Box 17)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1997-2007 (Box 17)
  - Ogilvy creative examples (Creative Update 2004; Red 2008 issue focusing on Dove's campaign with full-figured and non-model women)2004-2008 and undated (Box 17)
  - Photographs of David Ogilvy, undated (Box 17)
- Printed Materials, 1923-2011 and undated
  - 5 Giants of Advertising. Lorin, Philippe. Assouline, Paris, 2001 (Box 18)
  - 100 Leo's: Wit & Wsdom from Leo Burnett. Burnett, Leo. NTC Business Books, Chicago, Ill., 1995 (Box 18)
  - Adcult USA: The Triumph of Advertising in American Culture. Twitchell, James B.. Columbia University Press, New York, N.Y., 1996 (Box 18)
  - Advertising Age: 50 Years of TV Advertising Special Collectors Edition. Crain Communications, Chicago, Ill., Spring 1995 (Box 18)
  - Adweek: Special Anniversary Issue (20th). Prometheus Global Media, New York, N.Y., 1998 (Box 18)
  - Adweek: The Voice of Media- Vol. LII No. 23 June 13-June 19 2011. Prometheus Global Media, New York, N.Y., 2011 (Box 18)
  - All Out of Step: A Personal Chronicle. Lambert, Gerald B.. Doubleday & Company, Inc., Garden City, N.Y., 1956 (Box 18)
  - The Art of Writing Advertising: Conversations with Masters of the Craft. Interviewed by Higgins, Denis. NTC Business Books, Lincolnwood, Ill., 1995 (Box 18)
  - American Advertising 1800-1900. Americana Review, Scotia, N.Y., 1960 (Box 18)
  - The American Demands for British Goods, Benson Advisory Council for the Development of British Trade, S.H. Benson, Ltd., London, undated (Box 18)
  - Around & About Horsley. Horsley Countryside Preservation Society, West Horsley.2007 (Box 18)
  - A Big Life (in advertising). Lawrence, Mary Wells. Alfred A. Knopf New York, N.Y., 2002 (Box 18)
  - Bill Bernbach said..., DDB Needham Worldwide, New York, N.Y., undated (Box 18)
  - Born Fighting: How the Scots-Irish Shaped America. Webb, James. Broadway Books, New York, N.Y., 2004 (Box 18)
  - C: The Secret Life of Sir Stewart Menzies, Spymaster to Winston Churchill. Brown, Anthony Cave. Macmillan Publishing Co., New York, N.Y., 1987 (Box 18)
  - A Century of Change: A Surrey Village in the 20th Century. Bowley, Pam. Horse & Tree Publications, West Horsley, 2003 (Box 18)
  - Christ Church 2005, TJ International Ltd., Padstow, Cornwall, 2005 (Box 18)
  - East Horsley: The Lovelace Village. [Photographs] Bowley, Pam. Horsley Countryside Preservation Society, West Horsley, 2006 (Box 18)
  - The Fettes List 1870-1992. Old Fettesian Computer Center, Edinburgh, 1993 (Box 18)
  - George Gallup in Hollywood. Ohmer, Susan. Columbia University Press, New York, N.Y., 2006 (Box 18)
  - Having it All. Korda, Reva. First Signet Printing, Middlesex, England, 1991 (Box 18)
  - A History of Salisbury Township, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania. Lorenz, Joan M.. Masthof Press, Morgantown, Pa., 2002 (Box 18)
  - A History of the Publicity Club of London. Garth, Alan. C. Nicholls & Company Ltd., Great Britain, 1978 (Box 18)
  - How to Advertise. Roman, Ken and Maas, Jane. Thomas Dunne Books, New York, N.Y., 2003 (Box 18)
  - The Irregulars: Roald Dahl and the British Spy Ring in Wartime Washington. Conant, Jennet. Simon & Schuster, New York, N.Y., 2008 (Box 18)
  - J. Walter Takeover: From Divine Right to Common Stock. Morgan, Richard. Richard D. Irwin, Inc., Homewood, Ill., 1991 (Box 18)
  - The King of Madison Avenue: David Ogilvy and the Making of Modern Advertising. Roman, Kenneth. Palgrave Macmillan, New York, N.Y., 2009 (Box 18)
  - The King of Madison Avenue (Chinese). Roman, Kenneth. Bardon-Chinese Media Agency, Taipei, Taiwan, 2011 (Box 18)
  - The King of Madison Avenue: David Ogilvy and the Making of Modern Advertising (Chinese). Roman, Kenneth. China Citic Press, Beijing, 2010 (Box 18)
  - David Ogilvy: The King of Madison Avenue (German). Roman, Kenneth. Campus Verlag, Frankfurt, Germany, 2010 (Box 18)
  - David Ogilvy: The King of Madison Avenue (Spanish). Roman, Kenneth. Gestion, Barcelona, Spain, 2010 (Box 18)
  - The King of Madison Avenue (Russian). Roman, Kenneth, INFOX, Moscow, 2010 (Box 18)
  - Leo. Collection of Leo Burnett. Leo Burnett Company, Inc. Chicago, Ill., 1971 (Box 19)
  - The Longevity Factor: The New Reality of Long Careers and How it Can Lead to Richer Lives. Bronte, Lydia. HarperCollins Publishers, Inc., New York, N.Y., 1993 (Box 19)
  - Madame: an intimate biography of Helena Rubinstein. O'Higgins, Patrick. Redwood Press Limited, London, 1971 (Box 19)
  - Madison Avenue U.S.A.. Mayer, Martin. NTC Business Books, Lincolnwood, Ill., 1992 (Box 19)
  - Marion Harper: An Unauthorized Biography. Johnston, Russ. Crain Books, Chicago, Ill., 1982 (Box 19)
  - Murder Must Advertise. Sayers, Dorothy L.. HarperCollins Publishers, Inc., New York, N.Y., 1993 (Box 19)
  - OBM: 125 Years. Pigott, Stanley. Ogilvy Benson & Mather Limited, London, 1975 (Box 19)
  - Obvious Adams: The Story of a Successful Businessman. Updegraff, Robert R. Executive Development Press, Inc. Littleton, NH, 1953 (Box 19)
  - Old West Horsley: The Story of a Surrey Village. Bowley, Pam. Horse & Tree Publications, West Horsley, 2000 (Box 19)
  - Pigeon Holes of Memory: The Life and Times of Dr. John Mackenzie. Shaw, Christina Byam. Constable & Company Ltd., London, 1988 (Box 19)
  - The Power of The Idea. [Speech] Lewis, E. St. Elmo. Joseph D. McGuire, New York, N.Y., 1923 (Box 19)
  - Quotations of David Ogilvy. Ogilvy & Mather, New York, N.Y. (Box 19)
  - Rooted in Scotland. Taylor, Cameron. Luath Press Ltd., Edinburgh, 2007 (Box 19)
  - Rosanna of the Amish. Yoder, Joseph W.. Herald Press, Scottdale, Pa., 1993 (Box 19)
  - Scientific Advertising. Hopkins, Claude. Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide, New York, N.Y., 1993 (Box 19)
  - The Scoth-Irish: A Social History. Leyburn, James G.. The University of North Carolina Press, Chapel Hill, N.C., 1962 (Box 19)
  - The Secret History of British Intelligence in the Americas, 1940-45. British Security Coordination. Fromm International, New York, N.Y., 1999 (Box 19)
  - Spymistress: The Life of Vera Atkins, The Greatest Female Secret Agent of World War II. Stevenson, William. Arcade Publishing, Inc., New York, N.Y., 2007 (Box 19)
  - Star Reacher. Kufrin, Joan. Leo Burnett Company, Inc. Chicago, Ill., 1995 (Box 19)
  - The Story of West Horsley Manor and Its Church. Bowley, Pam. St. Mary's Church P.C.C., West Horsley, Surrey, 1993 (Box 19)
  - A Technique for Producing Ideas. Young, James Webb. NTC Business Books, Lincolnwood, Ill., 1986 (Box 19)
  - The Theory & Practice of Selling the Aga Cooker. Aga Heat Limited, Reissued by The Ogilvy Group, New York, N.Y., 1935 (Box 19)
  - Twenty Ads That Shook the World. Twitchell, James B.. Crown Publishers, New York, N.Y., 2000 (Box 19)
  - The Unpublished David Ogilvy: a selection of his writings from the files of his partners. The Ogilvy Group, Inc., 2002 (Box 19)
  - Up The Agency: The Funny Business of Advertising. Mayle, Peter. Pan Books, Great Britain, 1990 (Box 19)
  - The US Government, Citizen Groups and the Cold War. Edited by Laville, Helen and Wolford, Hugh. Routledge, New York, N.Y., 2006 (Box 19)
  - Whatever Happened to Madison Avenue?: Advertising in the '90s. Mayer, Martin. Little, Brown and Company, Boston, Mass., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Writing that Works: How to Communicate Effectively in Business. Roman, Kenneth and Raphaelson, Joel. HarperCollins Publishers, Inc., New York, N.Y., 2000 (Box 19)
  - Ogilvy on Ogilvy. Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide, New York, N.Y., 2003 (Box 20)
  - The Lasker Story: As He Told It. Lasker, Albert Davis. Advertising Publications, Inc., Chicago, Ill., 1963 (Box 20)
  - The Story of a Kitchen Classic. James, Tim. Absolute Press, England, 2002 (Box 20)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1935-2011 and undated
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restrictions on Access: Original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced. Contact Research Services for further information.
  - Interview cassettes
    Scope and Contents note
    Originals are closed to research. Transcripts of interviews are available in the collection.
    - Abbott, David. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Adams, Tony. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2005 (Box 21)
    - Aldred, Clive. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Barnett, Bernard. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Bartlett, Lee. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Bassat, Luis. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2007 (Box 21)
    - Baulk, Michael. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Begley, Louis. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Benson, Jimmy. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Biel, Alex (Tape 1). Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Biel, Alex (Tape 2). Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Biklen, Paul. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Binzen, Bill/Gaile. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Bird, Drayton. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Boumeisler, Doug. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Buck, Sue. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Bullmore, Jeremy. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Burson - Mitchell. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)
    - Carroll, Phil. Cassette. TRT: 90.00. 2006 (Box 21)